# Michael Uzoegwu . Jarvis Consulting

Donec mattis sed justo et sagittis. Vestibulum lacinia nulla ipsum. Curabitur imperdiet nibh vitae leo lacinia laoreet. Nullam accumsan, lectus ut maximus ultricies, augue justo egestas mi, vel bibendum felis.

#### Skills

**Proficient:** JavaScript / TypeScript, Angular, React, Python, HTML/CSS, Node.js, Git **Competent:** PostgreSQL, Firebase, AWS, C++, Express.js, MongoDB, Java, Linux/Bash

Familiar: C#, Qt, Selenium, WebPack, OpenGL, Pandas, Numpy

### **Jarvis Projects**

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis\_data\_eng\_MichaelUzoegwu

Cluster Monitor [GitHub]: Enabled the Linux Cluster Administration (LCA) team to collect and store hardware specifications and system usage data of a Rocky Linux cluster of 10 nodes. This data was gathered using Bash scripts and persisted in a PostgreSQL database running within a Docker container.

### **Highlighted Projects**

MyResume [GitHub]: Developed an online resume builder using React and Google Firebase to facilitate the creation of my resumes as PDFs. The idea was born out of a need to ensure visual consistency of my customized resume template across content-differing versions. Firebase was used to implement user authentication and resume storage, allowing users to manage multiple versions of their resumes. I used this application exclusively for over two years to create resumes, which contributed to securing multiple internships.

Last Resort: Worked as part of a team of three on a 2D platformer-shooter game built with OpenGL and C++, where my main responsibilities were centered around interactions between game entities and the environment. I developed terrain rendering from level data stored in CSV files and implemented an efficient method for detecting collisions between game entities and terrain. Additionally, I applied Dijkstra?s pathfinding algorithm to determine optimal movement for enemy AI agents.

MulBot [GitHub]: Created an X (formerly Twitter) bot with Python to tweet team lineups of the Manchester United soccer team in a more user-friendly format. The bot retrieves game start times and team lineups, ordered by player positions (instead of shirt numbers), through the API-Football. The start times are used to dynamically set a cron job that triggers the bot to tweet. The application was deployed on a remote Linux machine via DigitalOcean.

#### Professional Experiences

Software Developer, Jarvis (2024-Present): Donec mattis sed justo et sagittis. Vestibulum lacinia nulla ipsum. Curabitur imperdiet nibh vitae leo lacinia laoreet. Nullam accumsan, lectus ut maximus ultricies, augue justo egestas mi, vel bibendum felis.

Software Engineer Intern, SurveyMonkey (2022-2022): Donec mattis sed justo et sagittis. Vestibulum lacinia nulla ipsum. Curabitur imperdiet nibh vitae leo lacinia laoreet. Nullam accumsan, lectus ut maximus ultricies, augue justo egestas mi, vel bibendum felis.

Software QA Intern, ABB (2022-2022): Donec mattis sed justo et sagittis. Vestibulum lacinia nulla ipsum. Curabitur imperdiet nibh vitae leo lacinia laoreet. Nullam accumsan, lectus ut maximus ultricies, augue justo egestas mi, vel bibendum felis.

Software Developer Intern, UKG (2021-2021): Donec mattis sed justo et sagittis. Vestibulum lacinia nulla ipsum. Curabitur imperdiet nibh vitae leo lacinia laoreet. Nullam accumsan, lectus ut maximus ultricies, augue justo egestas mi, vel bibendum felis.

Software Developer Intern, Autodesk (2021-2021): Donec mattis sed justo et sagittis. Vestibulum lacinia nulla ipsum. Curabitur imperdiet nibh vitae leo lacinia laoreet. Nullam accumsan, lectus ut maximus ultricies, augue justo egestas mi, vel bibendum felis.

# Education

Carleton University (2018-2023), Bachelor of Computer Science, Computer Science - Carleton University Entrance Scholarship - Dean's List (2019) - GPA: 3.37/4.0

George Brown College (2024-Present), Certificate, Practical AI and Machine Learning

## Miscellaneous

- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate
- Soccer Fan
- Sci-fi Enthusiast